Thank you so much.
That looks fabulous.
Thank you, Geoffrey.
You're welcome.
We'll also take a bottle of red
as well. Thank you.
Certainly.
Right, now...
Thank you, Barry.
You're welcome.
Thank you.
That looks wonderful.
Beautiful day.
Where are you going?
To eat my sandwich.
You'll ruin your appetite for prawns.
I don't like prawns.
Darling, don't wander off.
For God's sake,
leave her alone, Deirdre.
Go play with your ball.
Don't be so annoying!
Darling, what about snakes?
There aren't any snakes on the beach.
Just let her enjoy herself for once.
Edward?
Yes, ma'am.
Hello, there.
What are you,
a little bird or something?
Are you hungry?
Take a bite. It's roast beef.
It's good. Come on.
I won't hurt you.
Mommy! Daddy! You've got to
come see this! I found something!
Cathy, darling, lunch is ready!
Are you looking at this?
I'm afraid there isn't enough
to go around.
Paul?
Cathy?
Will you hurry up?
Hurry up!
You're him, right?
Excuse me?
The scientist? The guy?
I saw you on TV.
I believed you.
Who shall I tell Mr. Hammond
is calling?
Ian Malcolm.
I've been summoned.
Dr. Malcolm!
Oh, my God.
Hello, Dr. Malcolm.
Kids, kids.
It's so great to see you.
It's so great.
Look at you.
You came to see Grandpa?
Yeah, he called me.
Do you know what it's about?
I don't, either. This joint's
kind of creepy, isn't it?
Is everything okay?
Well, not exactly.
Dr. Malcolm.
Dr. Malcolm. Here to share a few
campfire stories with my uncle?
You can convince The Washington Post
and Skeptical Inquirer
of whatever you want.
But I was there. I know
what happened and so do you.
Do you actually believe that
everyone who chose discretion did so
for a nefarious motive?
Even Lex and Tim?
Leave them out of it.
It's not a game.
No. You signed
a nondisclosure agreement
before you went to the island
that forbade you from
discussing what you saw.
You violated that agreement.
I did. And you lied about
the deaths of three people.
You misinformed the public,
which made me look like a nut.
Hasn't been so good
for my livelihood...
We made a generous compensatory offer
for your injuries.
A payoff and an insult.
When you spin reality,
cover up evidence,
it hurts more than my reputation.
As I recall,
your university revoked your tenure
for your selling wild stories
to the press.
I didn't sell anything. I never
took a cent, and I told the truth.
Your version of it.
There aren't any "versions"
of the truth.
InGen can't keep spewing out...
InGen is my responsibility now.
I will jealously defend
its interests.
Your responsibility?
What about Mr. Hammond?
It is our board of directors
I must face, not my uncle.
Trust me, your problems are
about to be rendered moot.
In a few weeks' time,
they'll be long forgotten.
Not by me.
Careful.
This suit cost more
than your education.
You were right and I was wrong.
There!
Did you ever expect
to hear me say such a thing?
Thank God for Site B.
Site B?
Isla Nublar was just a showroom,
something for the tourists.
Site B was the factory floor.
That was on Isla Sorna,
80 miles from Nublar.
We bred the animals there,
and nurtured them for a few months,
then moved them into the park.
Really? I did not know that.
After the accident in the park,
Hurricane Clarissa wiped out
our facility on Site B.
Call it an act of God.
We had to evacuate.
The animals were released
to mature on their own.
Life will find a way,
as you once so eloquently put it.
By now we have a complete
ecological system on the island
with dozens of species
living in their own social groups
without fences, boundaries,
or constraining technology.
And for four years
I've tried to keep it safe
from human interference.
That's right. Hopefully,
you've kept the island
quarantined and contained.
But I'm in shock about all this.
I mean, that they're still alive.
You bred them lysine-deficient.
Shouldn't they have kicked
after seven days
without supplemental enzymes?
Yes! But, by God,
they're flourishing.
That's one of 1,000 questions
I want the team to answer.
Team?
Yes.
I've organized an expedition to go in,
and, thank you,
and document them.
To make the most
spectacular living fossil record
the world has ever seen.
Go in and document?
You mean with people?
Yes, the animals won't even know
they're there. Very low impact.
Strictly observation
and documentation.
Our satellite infrareds show that
the animals are fiercely territorial.
The carnivores are isolated
in the interior of the island
so the team can stay
on the outer rim.
Don't worry. I'm not making
the same mistakes again.
No, you're making all new ones.
John!
Okay. So, there's another island
with dinosaurs,
no fences this time,
and you want to send people in,
very few people,
on the ground, right?
Who are these four lunatics
that you're trying to con into this?
It was difficult to convince them
as to what they would see,
in the end had to use my checkbook
to get them there.
But there's Nick Van Owen,
who is a video documentarian.
Eddie Carr,
who's a field equipment expert.
We have our paleontologist
and I was hoping that perhaps
you might be the fourth.
We've been on the verge of Chapter 11
ever since that accident in the park.
There are those in the company
who wanted to exploit Site B
in order to bail us out.
They've been planning it for years,
and I've been able
to stop them until now.
But, a few weeks ago,
a British family on a yacht cruise
stumbled across the island
and their wee girl was injured.
She's fine. She's fine.
But the board has used the incident
to take control of InGen from me.
Now it's only a matter
of time before this
lost world is found and pillaged.
Public opinion is the one thing
I can use to preserve it,
but to rally that support
I need a complete photo record
of those animals alive
and in their natural habitat.
So you went from capitalist
to naturalist in just four years.
That's something.
It's our last chance at redemption.
John,
no.
Of course, no.
And I'm going to contact the other
three members of your team
and stop them from going.
Who's the paleontologist, by the way?
She came to me,
I want you to know this.
Who did?
Leave it to you, Ian,
to have associations, affiliations,
even liaisons, with the best people
in so many fields.
Not Sarah.
Paleontological behavior study
is a new field,
and Sarah Harding
is on that frontier.
Her theories on
parenting and nurturing
amongst carnivores
have framed the debate.
What are you doing?
Where's your phone?
It's too late.
She's already there.
The others are meeting her
in three days.
You sent my girlfriend
to this island alone?
Sent is hardly the word.
She couldn't be restrained.
She was already working in San Diego,
doing some research
at the animal park.
It's only a couple of hours flight
from there.
She was adamant, absolutely
adamant about, here you are,
about making the initial foray
by herself.
She thinks she's Dian Fossey.
Observation without interference,
she said.
She went on and on.
You know how it is.
After you were injured in the park,
she sought you out.
Then she went all the way
to a hospital in Costa Rica
to ask somebody who she didn't even know
if the rumors were true.
If you want to leave your name
on something, fine.
But stop putting it on
other people's headstones.
She'll be fine. She's spent
years studying African predators.
Sleeping downwind and all.
She knows what she's doing.
And, believe me,
the research team will...
It's not a research expedition
anymore.
It's a rescue operation
and it's leaving now.
You can't shave three days
off my deadline
and expect to be ready.
I'm not fully supplied.
I haven't tested any of this.
Why give her a satellite phone
if it doesn't work?
Could be solar flares, the satellite,
or maybe she turned it off.
I need half air on the tires.
We're flying pressurized.
Does she know how to use it?
You kidding?
She's faxed me refinements on
50% of the plans for this stuff.
Don't do that. You got to baby
it a little bit. Love it.
I'll love it when it works.
It'll work when you love it.
You coming along?
I don't usually, but I can't resist.
Thanks for the two-minute warning.
Nick Van Owen, this is Ian Malcolm.
Nick's our field photographer.
How do you do?
You do wildlife photography?
Wildlife, combat, you name it.
When I was with Nightline,
I was in Rwanda, Chechnya, Bosnia.
I do volunteer work with Greenpeace
once in a while.
Greenpeace?
What drew you there?
Women.
80% female, Greenpeace.
Noble.
Noble was last year.
This year I'm getting paid.
Hammond's check cleared, or I wouldn't
go on this wild-goose chase.
You're going to the only place in the world
where the geese chase you.
Dad! Dad!
Kelly, my honey, you found it.
What took you so long?
Sorry, I couldn't get a cab.
Sweetie, that's okay.
Listen, I've got to tell you something.
I've got to talk to you.
I don't even know this woman.
You've known Karen for 10 years.
She doesn't even have Sega.
She's such a troglodyte.
Cruel, but good word use.
Why can't I stay with Sarah?
She's out of town.
Karen's fantastic.
She'll take you places.
You'll have a fantastic time.
Stop saying "fantastic".
Where are you going, anyway?
It's only for a few days. I wouldn't
be going if it wasn't really important.
I'm your daughter all the time.
You can't abandon me
whenever opportunity knocks.
That hurts my feelings.
Your mom tell you to say that?
Dr. Malcolm, downstairs, please.
I know we've had some hard going.
But in the last few years,
we've started to work things out.
Yeah, but crack on me a bit.
Ground me or something.
Send me to my room.
You never do any of that stuff.
Why would I?
You turned out so
beautiful, brilliant, powerful,
funny, and generous.
The queen, goddess.
My inspiration.
Dr. Malcolm.
I could come be your research assistant,
like I was in Austin.
This is nothing like Austin.
Anyway, you have your own stuff.
Your gymnastics competition.
You've been training for months.
Gymnastics?
I scrubbed out, Dad,
I got cut from the team.
Thanks for knowing.
I'm sorry, honey.
I know how much that meant to you.
You like to have kids, but you just
don't want to be with them, do you?
Hey, I'm not the one
who dumped you here
and split for Paris,
so don't take it out on me.
Dr. Malcolm, downstairs!
Honey, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
You want some good parental advice?
Don't listen to me.
How are we doing here?
The specs say it can't deform at
12,000 PSI, so we just have to test it.
Let's clear. Are we clear?
What's this?
A High Hide.
A High Hide. You know,
you go up and hide, high.
It goes up to where the trees are
and keeps the researchers
out of harm's way.
Actually, it puts them at
a very convenient biting height.
What's the time?
Do you have the time?
Do I have the time? Why?
We're leaving in three hours.
This is so cool.
Lindstradt air rifle fires a subsonic
Fluger impact delivery dart.
It works better than
your satellite phone?
That's funny.
I loaded it with the enhanced venom
of Conus Purpurascens,
South Sea cone shell.
Most powerful neurotoxin
in the world.
Acts within 0.002 of a second.
Which is faster than
the nerve-conduction velocity.
So the animal's down before
it even feels the prick of the dart.
Is there an antidote?
Like if you shot yourself
in the foot?
Don't do that.
You'd be dead before you even realized
you had an accident.
The guy says that he wants to unload
at the shore, right here.
He won't go any further up the river.
He's heard too many stories
about this island chain,
and he wants to drop us off
and go anchor somewhere offshore.
What kind of stories?
He's heard stories of fishermen
that came too close to the island
and never returned.
He has a radio.
He has a satellite phone.
When you need him, send a call
and he'll be here in two hours.
But he will not stay here.
He won't stay anywhere
near these islands.
They call the islands...
"Las Cinco Muertes"?
What does that mean?
The Five Deaths,
he says.
I put a location sensor
into Dr. Harding's satellite phone,
so we should get a reading.
Yeah, I'm so relieved.
Don't push my buttons.
We're almost on top of her dot.
She should be around here.
Over there.
Sarah!
Sarah Harding!
How many Sarahs do you think
are on this island?
What?
Something big.
This is magnificent.
Yeah...
That's how it always starts.
But then later there's
running and screaming.
Nick!
I guess you got the jump on us,
didn't you, Sarah?
Yeah.
Ian, I never thought
in a million years
Hammond could get you to come here.
Hi, Eddie.
Hi, Sarah.
Got a granola bar or something?
I'm starving.
Did you see those animals?
A family group,
a pair-bond and a sub-adult,
long after the juvenile
was nest bound.
Every egg clutch I've seen
has crushed, trampled shells.
Hatchlings stay in the birth environment
a long time.
That's conclusive.
I can put that controversy to rest
if I get a shot of the nest.
Have you been attacked?
No, that's my lucky pack.
That's how it always looks.
Okay, Sarah...
Is that a Nikon?
Can I borrow that?
I'll be right back, baby, I promise.
When Hammond called you,
why didn't you say something to me?
I knew you would have
stopped me from coming.
I would have tied you to the bed.
I know how they survived
without lysine.
I don't care.
The herbivore species
that are thriving
eat mostly agama beans,
soy, anything lysine-rich.
And the carnivores eat
the herbivores, so...
Wait.
Stay there. Be quiet.
I'll be right back.
No!
Stay there.
She's much too close.
What the hell is she doing?
Too close.
She has to touch it.
She can't not touch.
She's going right up to it.
Once she sees something,
she has to...
Is this even possible?
What?
This? What did you
think you'd document?
What did you think you'd see?
Animals, maybe,
big iguanas.
Fruitcakes.
They get very angry
when you run out of film.
Sarah!
Shoot them!
They're just protecting their baby.
So am I!
I think they're leaving.
These images are incredible.
Legendary.
Guys shoot their whole life,
they never get stuff half this good.
Just give me the Pulitzer right now.
Today, please.
The competition's over,
close the entries,
I'd like to thank everyone who lost.
Don't light that! Dinosaurs pick
up scents from miles away.
We're here to observe
and document, not interact.
Which, by the way,
is a scientific impossibility.
Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle.
What you study, you also change.
I'll risk it. I'm sick of scratching
around in rock and bone,
and making assumptions
and deductions about
the nurturing habits of animals that
have been dead for 65 million years.
I'm sick of it, man.
Then you show up and fill my head
with stories for four years,
so of course I'm going to
come down here.
Stories of mutilation and death.
Weren't you paying attention?
Please! Don't treat me like
I'm a grad student.
I've worked around predators
since I was 20 years old.
Lions, jackals, hyenas, you.
Where's the fire?
I'm trying to change 100 years
of entrenched dogma.
Dinosaurs were characterized
very early on as vicious lizards.
There's great resistance to the idea
of them as nurturing parents.
Robert Burke said
the T-Rex was a rogue
who abandoned its young
at the earliest opportunity.
I know I can prove otherwise.
Fire! Dr. Malcolm!
Fire, base camp!
No! Water makes the smoke billow.
Use dirt!
Who started the fire?
I just wanted to make dinner.
I wanted it ready
when you guys got back.
Do you see any family
resemblance there?
You practically told me to come here.
I... what?
You said, don't listen to me.
I thought you were trying
to tell me something.
Kelly, you knew exactly what I meant.
You have no...
You want to lock her up
for her curiosity?
Where do you think she gets it?
Thank you, Sarah.
Don't start the teaming-up thing
about this.
Out of the conversation.
Please.
Really. Eddie?
What?
Why in the hell
doesn't this thing ever work?
It's not a landline.
You're not in a phone booth.
You got to wait for a decent signal.
Violence and technology,
not good bedfellows.
The kind of documentation
Hammond wants
is you and your equipment in the field
as close to the animals as safely possible.
Yeah, that's a great idea.
And while you're at it,
why don't you smear yourself
with a little sheep's blood?
Eddie, is there any reason to think that
the radio in the trailer might work?
Don't tease me.
If you feel qualified at all,
you might try flicking the switch to on.
Okay, I'm taking my daughter
out of here.
Anybody who wants to come with me,
this is your last chance to get out.
When you're out in the field...
Nick, if you're staying,
I'd be happy to deliver
a letter to your wife or loved one
so you can say goodbye.
Eddie, if you have
any personal effects.
It's the least I can do.
I'll be in there, guys.
Our presence needs to be
100% antiseptic.
If we so much as bend
a blade of grass...
Dad, are you mad?
No, I'm not mad. I'm furious.
What is this?
This looks like your room.
I was going to clean it up.
Right now.
What is this?
There are 100 switches!
Ian, don't be mad. I was going to
call to let you know where I was.
I always do, don't I?
Come on. I'm the best kind
of girlfriend there is.
One who travels a lot.
You like that, right?
You love your independence.
Well, I've gotten used to being apart,
but that doesn't mean that
that's how I want to live.
Kelly, this is tall talk.
Just for a minute.
It's like a height restriction
at an amusement park.
If you wanted to rescue me
from something,
why didn't you bail me out
of that fundraiser at the museum
three weeks ago,
like you said you would?
This is a slightly
different situation.
What about the dinner with your parents
you never showed up for?
Why not rescue me
when I really need it?
Be there when you say you will?
I have made a career
out of waiting for you.
You know, Sarah has a pretty good...
It's so important to your future
that you not finish that sentence.
Please, outside!
Ian, come on. Look.
I love that you rode in here
on a white horse. I really do.
It's very touching, very dramatic.
I just need you to show up in a cab
every once in a while, too.
What are you doing?
Don't go out there. It's not safe.
Stay in here. Come back.
Shut the door.
Okay.
I know what I'm doing.
You guys should definitely go.
But I'm going to stay.
I love you. I just don't
need you right now.
What you need is
a good anti-psychotic.
I'll be back in five or six days.
No, you'll be back
in five or six pieces.
What bothers you is that I'm not afraid
of this place, and you are.
Of course I am. That's the whole thing.
All I want is...
What's that sound?
Here we go. I'll get you
out on one of these, now.
Hello! Over here!
I don't get it. It says InGen
on the side of that chopper!
I don't get that. Why would
Hammond send two teams?
Cut the umbilical, Dad!
Doesn't he trust us?
We haven't even started.
This is as good a place as any
for base camp.
That's first priority
after we're finished.
I want it up and running in 30 minutes.
That's half an hour.
Understood? Over.
Cancel that order.
What? Why?
This is a game trail, Mr. Ludlow.
Carnivores hunt on game trails.
You want to set up
base camp or a buffet?
Let's find a new spot, shall we?
Over and out.
Peter, if I run your little camping trip,
there are two conditions.
First, I'm in charge.
If I'm not around, Dieter is.
You just pay us,
tell us we're doing well,
and serve us Scotch after a good day.
Second condition, my fee.
You can keep it.
All I want for my services,
is the right to hunt a Tyrannosaurus.
A male. A buck only.
How and why are my business.
If you don't like those conditions,
you're on your own.
So go ahead, set up base camp here,
in a swamp, or in the middle of
a Rex nest for all I care.
I've had too many safaris
with rich dentists
to listen to any more suicidal ideas.
Okay?
Okay.
Cycle, break off the stray from the herd
and flush him to the right.
Snaggers, stay ready. He's bringing
them out to you. It'll be a...
Pachy... Pachya...
Oh, hell.
The fat head with the bald spot.
Friar Tuck.
Stop.
Pachycephalosaurus.
Carnivore?
No, herbivore, late Cretaceous.
See the distinctive domed skull?
Nine inches of solid bone.
Now, careful.
See, the Pachy's neck attaches
at the bottom of its skull,
instead of at the back of its head,
as with reptiles.
When it lowers its head, its neck
lines up directly with its backbone,
which is perfect
for absorbing impact.
Snagger, Friar Tuck's on the loose,
just about to cross your path.
Dieter, get in the outrigger.
You're closing in on a...
Say that again, Roland.
A what?
The one with the big red horn.
The pompadour. Elvis.
Take me out.
Okay, Carter, reel me in.
Easy!
Not too close.
Go for the legs!
The legs! Watch the tail!
Burke!
Come here.
You recognize this trackway?
Yes, I do. Tyrannosaur.
Roland.
Where do you think you're going?
To collect my fee, Mr. Ludlow.
To collect my fee.
Oh, my God.
Procompsognathus Triassicus,
found by Frass in Bavaria in 1913.
Is it dangerous?
No, I wouldn't think so.
The Compy's been presumed
to be a scavengers, like jackals.
It gives me the creeps.
It's like it's not scared.
There haven't been any visitors
to this island.
There's no reason for it to fear man.
Now it does.
It's the Rex nest.
Infant's probably only
a couple weeks old.
Never left the nest.
Offspring that young, the parents
won't leave him alone for too long.
Make your blind here,
wait for the buck to return.
No, if the nest is upwind,
then so are we.
When he comes back, he's gonna know
we're here without us having a chance.
The trick is...
to get him to come
where we want him.
This is why Hammond
was in such a hurry to get you here.
He knew they were coming.
My God, they are well-organized.
Those are some major-league toys.
Maybe I should ask
to use their phone.
Their dish is bigger than yours.
So they actually want to
build another park here?
After what you said happened
on the other island?
They're not building anything.
They're taking these animals
out of here.
Back to the mainland.
I think I should tell you, guys.
Hammond told me these people
might show up.
He thought we'd be finished
by the time they got started,
but in case they weren't,
he did send a backup plan.
What backup plan?
Me.
Simply put, InGen is seeking
limited partners
to defray some of our expenses.
The prospectus you've been given
by the board details
our projected hardware
and construction expenses.
As you can see
by my two friends here,
the software is already
fully developed.
One might say,
it'd be up and running.
In a moment, I'll take you
on a stroll through the camp
and you'll see some larger,
more impressive specimens.
You don't bring people halfway
around the world to visit a zoo.
You bring the zoo to them.
San Diego is the perfect setting.
People already associate our
beautiful city with animal attractions.
San Diego Zoo, Sea World,
San Diego Chargers.
Mr. Hammond knew this.
Before he ever dreamt of an island
he began construction
on an amphitheatre,
very near to where you're sitting now,
the InGen Waterfront Complex.
But he abandoned it
in favor of something far grander
and ultimately impossible.
And so, the facility sits unused,
unfinished,
when it could be completed and ready
to receive visitors
in less than a month.
Ajay, look out! Jump!
That's the last time
I leave you in charge.
Oh, my God.
Are you out of your mind?
She's got a broken leg.
Let's get in the car
before they hear us.
You have any idea what that is?
Come on, open the door.
You're nuts.
Man, Ian's not going to like this.
What's going on?
Isn't it obvious?
We're not alone on this island.
It's not set to the frequency.
Look here.
What the hell is that?
It's right here. Hello?
No, not Enrique. Ian Malcolm.
Are you on the boat?
No, is this the boat?
We're on Isla Sorna. We need to
talk to the boat, Mar del Plata.
I'll get him.
All right. That's it.
I got you.
Hurry up.
Let's go. Go. Come on.
Watch his tail. Get the door.
Boy, is she mad at you.
I feel sorry for that guy, Enrique.
No lectures, please.
Honey, stay back.
Don't stand up, okay?
I got it!
Watch his head.
Ian, he's hurt!
No, honey, no.
I'm going to get the table.
He'll snip at you. Watch his tail,
he's swinging his tail.
Set him down.
All right?
Okay, I got him.
Got him?
Yeah.
It's okay.
There you go.
What must I do, hit her with a stick?
No, don't get close, honey.
Watch out!
Don't stand too close.
He smells.
No, lady, enough!
Wrong frequency. God.
Nick, don't let him get
those things around you.
Hello, it's Ian Malcolm.
Okay, let's take a look at this.
Easy, easy.
Just calm down now.
Okay, here are the metatarsals.
Tibia, fibula. There it is.
There's the fracture.
Right above the epiphysis.
How bad is it?
If we don't set it, he'll die.
It won't heal.
He won't be able to pivot
on his ankle.
He won't be able to run or walk.
A predator will pick him off.
Carlos, come in.
God damn it, you bastard, listen...
Other animals are going to hear this.
Come in, please.
Can you hear me?
I've got to get out of here.
I want to leave.
I'm calling the boat.
I want to go someplace else.
I don't want to be here.
I want to be somewhere safe.
Isn't it safe here?
I want to be somewhere high.
What? What is it?
What's going on?
Information, please.
What?
You're much happier not knowing.
Get us up. Here we go.
There we go.
I'm so stupid. I shouldn't
have come along with you.
Can you set it?
Yeah, I just need something temporary
to break apart and fall off
as he grows.
Whenever you're ready.
He's fighting, Dr. Quinn.
What's the frequency for the boat?
15888.
It's third from the top.
Okay, we're high, and this is
the safest place you can be.
Like Sarah said before,
these plants make it
so the animals
won't even know you're here.
You're just trying
to make me feel better.
I remember all those stories
you told.
Oh, no, no.
This is nothing like that.
We're in a completely
different situation right now.
Is there any way we can communicate
with the trailer?
He's moving again, more morphine.
We have no idea what his metabolism is.
We'll kill him with too much.
I need your hand here.
Put some pressure there.
No answer. What a surprise.
How do I get down?
Tie this belt around you.
Where are you going?
Stay here. Come on,
stay here. Please!
Squeeze this rope hard.
The harder you squeeze,
the slower you go.
If you don't squeeze at all...
I get the idea.
Dad, please stay here.
Stay here, please.
Honey, the queen?
The goddess?
Your inspiration?
Now you're talking.
All right.
I'm coming right back.
I give you my word.
But you never keep your word!
I would have squeezed
just a little bit harder.
Okay, I'm almost finished.
Damn it.
I need another adhesive.
Something pliable that I can...
Spit.
Your gum.
Get the amoxicillin
and fill a syringe.
Quick injection of antibiotics
and he's out of here.
For once in your life,
would it kill you to pick it up?
Help me get it out of here.
No, we just set its leg.
Mommy's very angry.
This isn't hunting behavior, Ian.
They're searching.
They came for their infant.
Let's not disappoint them.
Let me get his head, okay?
Careful. Be careful.
I got him.
Muzzle off.
Yes, Eddie?
They're going back to the jungle.
I know. I see.
How's Kelly?
She's fine.
She's right here.
Hello?
Kelly, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm good.
Stay there. Don't move.
I'll be right back up. Understand?
Yeah, I understand.
I beg people to listen to me.
I use plain, simple English.
Shut up.
That should make an interesting
chapter in your book.
The debate over
the parental instincts
of the T-Rex is now academic.
Hang on.
This is gonna be bad.
They're pushing us over the cliff.
Oh, my God.
Come on, come on.
Once we're out of here...
Into the woods.
Straight into the woods.
Come on!
This is where they hit us.
Hang on to something!
Sarah!
Oh, God, please!
Don't move!
I'm coming down for you.
Here I come. Stay still.
Here I come, Sarah.
The satellite phone, get it!
Okay.
Give me your hand, honey.
Heads up!
Your lucky pack.
I got her.
Nick?
We're in here.
Hold on!
I'm coming.
God damn it!
What did this?
Kelly. What'd you do with Kelly?
She's okay.
She's in the High Hide.
Who's hurt? What do you need?
We need rope.
Rope. Anything else?
Three cheeseburgers with everything.
No onions on mine.
And an apple turnover.
Hold on.
I'm coming!
Bring the rope.
Let's go.
I'm coming.
Now, now.
Eddie, you all right?
Yeah. I'm coming.
We need the rope.
Throw it down here. Hurry up!
Good throw.
Did you tie this to anything?
We're sliding down!
Up you go.
Eddie! Hey!
Go.
Increase your rate of climb.
Our communication equipment's
been destroyed.
And if your radio and satellite phone
were in those trailers...
They were.
Then we're stuck here.
And stuck together,
thanks to you people.
We came to watch.
You came to strip-mine the place.
Back off.
At least we came prepared.
Five years of work and a hundred miles
of electrified fence
couldn't prepare the other island,
and you think that, what,
a couple dozen Marlboro men
were going to make a difference?
It's a looter mentality. All you care about
is what you can take. You have no right.
An extinct animal brought
back to life has no rights.
It exists because we made it.
We patented it. We own it.
You looking for a problem?
And I found you, didn't I?
Stop!
Come on!
I know you.
You're that Earth First bastard.
What's Earth First?
Professional saboteurs.
Environmentalists!
Criminals.
Knock it off!
Listen to me.
By moving the baby rex
into our camp
we may have changed
the adults' perceived territory.
Their what?
That's why they persisted
in destroying the trailers.
They now feel they have to
defend this entire area.
We have to move right now.
Move where?
Our boat, their airlift,
they're both waiting for an order
we have no way to send.
All right. All right.
There's a communications center here
near the old operations building.
Hammond ran everything
on geothermal power.
It was never meant
to need replenishing.
If we can get here, we can send
a radio call to the airlift.
You have the frequency
written down somewhere?
Right here in this book.
We'll mind those.
How far is the village?
A day's walk, maybe more.
That's not the problem.
What is?
What is the problem?
Velociraptors.
Our infrared show their nesting sites
are concentrated in the island's interior,
which is why we were planning to
keep to the outer rim.
What's a Veloc...
Velociraptor.
Carnivore. Pack hunter.
About two meters tall, long snout,
binocular vision, strong dexterous
forearms and killing claws on both feet.
And the Rexes may continue
to track us too,
if they feel we're a threat
to them or their infant.
No, no, you're wrong there, Dr. Harding,
we'll lose them once we leave their territory.
No, don't bet on it.
Tyrannosaur has got the largest
proportional olfactory cavity
of any creature in the fossil record,
with the exception of one.
Right.
The turkey vulture
could scent up to 10 miles.
Right. This is all very thrilling,
but I say we should push on
to the village.
We could head back down
to the lagoon.
And dow what?
Sit out in the open,
next to a heavily used water source
and hope that your captain comes back?
He won't do that. He knows better.
Then we head for the village,
we might find some shelter
and we can call for help.
Rex just fed,
so he won't stalk us for food.
Just fed? I assume
you're talking about Eddie?
You might show a little repsect.
The man saved our lives by giving his.
Then his troubles are over.
My point is that predators don't hunt
when they're not hungry.
No, only humans do.
Oh, you're breaking our heart.
Saddle up! Let's get this
moveable feast underway.
Excuse me, cowboy.
You want some gum?
You seem like you have
a shred of common sense.
What the hell are you doing here?
Somewhere on this island is the greatest
predator that ever lived.
The second greatest predator
must take him down.
You going to use that?
If he doesn't surrender, yes.
Let me see it for a second.
No.
The animal exists on the planet
for the first time
in tens of millions of years
and the only way you can
express yourself is to kill it.
Remember that chap about 20 years ago?
I forget his name.
Climbed Everest without any oxygen.
Came down nearly dead.
When they asked him,
why did you go up there to die?
He said, I didn't.
I went up there to live.
I haven't had a chance to wish you luck
on your new business venture.
You're off to a promising start.
My team is intact, doctor.
I'm sorry for the loss of your man.
You know, it's very easy
to criticize someone
who generates an idea,
someone who assumes all the risk.
When you try to sound like Hammond,
it just comes off like a hustle.
I mean, it's not your fault.
They say talent skips a generation, so...
Hey, I'm sure your kids
are going to be sharp as tacks.
Hammond's reach exceeded his grasp.
Mine does not.
Taking dinosaurs off this island
is the worst idea in the long,
sad history of bad ideas.
And I'm going to be there
when you learn that.
Go.
Take a break. Five minutes.
Are you injured?
No, it's from the baby.
I set its broken leg.
It's just not drying in the humidity.
Roland, a word?
I'd love to know where we are.
Making friends with Ahab, huh?
Hey, Carter, I'm going
to the ladies' room.
Wait for me here. Okay?
It's not polite
to sneak up on people.
Hey, Carter!
Where are you?
I got turned around in here.
Shit!
Hey, Carter, let me hear from you!
Hey, Carter!
Carter!
Hey, Roland!
Okay, break's over. Moving on!
Carry me.
Carter. Carter.
Get off!
When did you last see him?
10, 15 minutes.
Come with me. And you.
If he's alive, we'll find him.
The rest of you keep right on.
Ten minutes,
you should reach the ridge.
Wait for us there.
Miss Harding?
No one tells the little girl.
Right.
Let's carry on.
Everybody up.
Come on. Up, up, up.
All right, guys,
let's get the hell out of here.
Come on.
Roland?
Did you find him?
Just the parts they didn't like.
Map.
The operations building
is right down in there
about a mile and a half
from the base of these cliffs.
How do you know that?
I've seen it.
Now, the climb down won't be easy.
We'll let them sleep one more hour.
And then we hit it.
Oh, no.
What is that?
Kelly.
Stay down! Don't move!
Don't run!
Don't look!
Just run! Run, run, run!
Bastard!
You son of a bitch!
He can't reach you!
Stay back!
He can't reach us!
No!
Oh, my God!
A snake! Help me!
Stay back!
You're okay. You're okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's coming back!
Dad!
Thank you.
Don't go into the long grass!
Not into the long grass!
Hey, hey!
Look at this.
What is it?
I think it's Ajay's bag.
Go, as fast as you can.
Go!
I see structures there.
They said the communications center
is in the operations building.
So I'll just get in there and I'll send
the radio call. I'll see you there.
Wait for us.
Every second counts.
If anyone thinks they can keep up,
you're welcome to try.
Okay, here we come.
No! Ian, rest.
Oh, man.
Damn it!
Be there. Be there.
CQ, this is InGen Operations
Harvest Leader to Harvest Base.
Repeating, I'm calling for
InGen Operations Harvest Leader
seeking InGen Harvest Base.
Go ahead, Harvest Leader.
The operation has suffered
severe casualties.
The survivors are now
in mortal danger.
I need you to send rescue
immediately.
Our coordinates here are...
Our coordinates here are 9 degrees
58 minutes north, 85 degrees...
Nick!
Nick Van Owen?
Here, here, here!
Inside! Anywhere!
Go, go inside!
Go. Go!
Where do I go when I'm out?
I'm right behind you...
Look out! Look out!
Watch out!
Up here!
Kelly, no!
Hey, you!
The school cut you from the team?
Get out of here!
Get out of here! Go!
Come on. Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
What about the others?
There must be more survivors!
There's another chopper coming.
It's okay. It's over now.
That's one souvenir
they won't be taking with them.
Find the infant Tyrannosaur.
Roland can show you
where the nest is.
I want it on my jet.
I'll take it directly to the infirmary
at the complex in San Diego.
Hurry it up.
I'd love to be airborne
before the female knows we're here.
Roland? Roland?
You probably saved InGen.
We lost everything
we came after on this trip.
But this animal and its infant are going
to single-handedly bail us out.
Congratulations.
You've got your trophy!
A buck only. But it's alive!
And everyone one the planet
is going to line up
to appreciate it and everything
that you've done for us.
What's the matter?
He didn't make it. Ajay.
I'm sorry.
Really, I am.
I remember the people
who've helped me.
There's a job for you at the park
in San Diego, if you want it.
No, thank you.
I believe I've spent enough time
in the company of death.
Oh, my God.
Fifteen years ago,
John Hammond had a dream.
Like John himself,
the dream was grand.
It was outsized.
It was bold.
It was impractical.
It was not to be.
But half an hour from now,
John Hammond's dream,
re-imagined, will come true.
For 0.01 of the cost
of building a destination resort
thousands of miles away...
Hiya. Is this the Ludlow affair?
This is private property.
No, we're on the list, though.
You have to turn around,
get back in your car.
This is Dr. Harding,
I'm Dr. Malcolm.
We have Mr. Ludlow's
test results.
There's good and bad news.
Tonight we will christen
Jurassic Park, San Diego,
with a mega-attraction
that will drive turnstile numbers
to rival any theme park in the world.
I want to thank each one of you
for being intrepid enough to turn up
in these wee small hours
of the morning.
The ship, it's here.
It's early?
You better come now.
It's so exciting!
You see that couple?
Sir, you need to look at this.
Let them see this up close.
Yes, sir.
Let me check.
I want a direct line
to the Coast Guard right now.
Look. That's their transponder signal,
Venture 5888.
They're headed into port,
but I can't raise them.
Try again.
Skipper, SS Venture,
this is InGen Harbor Master.
Do you copy? Over.
Skipper, SS Venture, you are approaching
the breakwater at flank speed.
Reduce at once. Over.
SS Venture,
reduce your speed at once.
SS Venture, this is
InGen Harbor Master.
You are entering a docking area.
What's everybody looking at?
We should've stayed in the damn car.
You okay, Mr. Ludlow?
I don't know. How do I look?
Oh, my God.
Where's the crew?
All over the place.
Check the cargo hold!
There may be crew down there.
Everybody off the boat!
No, no! Get away from that!
Now you're John Hammond.
Why the hell wasn't it tranquilized?
It was, Roland hit it with two darts
of concentrated Carfentanil.
It was over 10 milligrams.
That should've put it into a coma.
It stopped breathing, so we gave it
Naltrexone to counteract the effects.
But we didn't know
how much to give it.
You administered an antagonist
without knowing the proper dosage?
You put the animal
in a narcoleptic state.
The thing's a locomotive now.
Look, we're prepared here...
Are there any more dinosaurs
still on the boat?
No, we brought the infant back
on the plane.
We had this to tranquilize it.
Do you have the infant?
It's safe.
Ian. The animal's dehydrated.
The first it's going to do
is go to a water source
and then it's going to look for
the next thing its body needs.
All the containment equipment is here.
We've got to get it back to the dock.
The boat might still be seaworthy.
I think I know what you're gonna say.
When we brought the baby
to the trailer, it came.
There's no reason to think
it won't do the same thing here.
Yep.
Where's the infant?
It's in a secured facility.
Why?
Where's the facility?
There's a dinosaur in our backyard.
Benjamin, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
What? What?
Come on. There's a dinosaur
in our backyard.
The problem is,
you need to read to him.
No, no, no.
I will tell you exactly what it is.
You have to serve him dinner,
he won't be up all night.
It's the stupid fish tank!
It is not the fish tank!
He needs a proper nightlight.
Then put something over it!
It may as well be daytime.
It isn't.
Just turn it off and...
Slow down. Slow it down!
There it is.
He's sedated.
Really heavily.
Give me a hand.
When the adult sees us
once again with his baby,
isn't he going to be like... You!
There may be some angry recognition.
Who knows?
He may be just happy to see us.
Hey! What the hell
do you think you're you doing?
We're taking the kid.
If you really want to stop us,
shoot us.
How will we find the adult?
Follow the screams.
Get to the other side of the bus!
There.
Oh, my God.
It's too drugged.
He's never going to know we have it
if the thing won't make
some kind of sound!
Come on. Wake up. Come on.
Come on. Wake up.
He knows.
Ian, slow down a little.
I don't think so.
This guy's almost fully awake.
You know where you're going?
Yeah, the waterfront's on
the other side of these warehouses.
Is there a way through?
God. There could be.
There we go.
You have to follow me now.
Got him?
Yep.
Here we go. Ready?
Where's the Rex?
Is it still behind us?
There's the water.
Shoot it. Shoot it.
Tell them to shoot it.
No, you idiot, the adult.
Shoot the adult.
I want the baby back alive.
Dr. Malcolm!
What have you done with it?
I want that infant!
Are you there?
There you are.
Wait. Wait.
There's a really first-rate shot
of the deck of this ship,
and the cargo hold that,
for the moment anyway,
contains the animal itself,
presumably with the infant alongside.
By our calculations, they should be
nearing the halfway point of this trip.
Jim, can you still hear me there?
Yes, I can, Bernard.
We are in fact halfway to the island.
It is 206 nautical miles
from our present location.
The ship is moving at about 20 knots
which will put it in at about
11:30 a.m., Eastern time.
One of the Navy's primary concerns
throughout all of this has been safety.
And if we take another look around
the ever-growing escort around the ship
they're taking no chances of a repeat
of the San Diego incident.
Okay. We're going to take
a moment here
and run the tape of our interview
earlier today with John Hammond.
He's the former head of
InGen Bio-Engineering,
the man who has come forward
to spearhead this movement
not only to return these animals
to their island
but to keep the island itself intact.
It is absolutely imperative
that we work with the Costa Rican
Department of Biological Preserves
to establish a set of rules
for the preservation
and isolation of that island.
These creatures require
our absence to survive,
not our help.
And if we could only step aside...
and trust in nature...
life will find a way.